

Hameed Ali

Muscat, Oman



h366989@gmail.com



0096891152074



linkedin.com/in/hameedali



www.hameedali.com

Summary:

15 years of leadership in hospitality cluster management, proudly managed legendary award-winning hotel of 16 outlets, 670 rooms, 650 employees, 33 meeting rooms, convention center, liquor store, commercial laundry, executive office building & Bahrain F1 catering. Achieved pre-opening in budget ranging size of \$10M to \$39M. Exploit a broad range of strategic, commercial, operational, transformational change & capex project leadership skills to shape and execute high-yield strategies which enhance operational effectiveness, customer experience and commercial gain.

Great fit character:

Strategic sales & marketing plans | Budget & forecast control | Operation management | Pre-opening hotel projects | E-commerce & OTA's | Social media | Communications & Influencing | Guests experiences | Skills training programs | Change & capex management | SOP, P&P policies | Revenue, distribution & optimization management | Culinary | Cost efficiency & profit maximization.

Experience:

General Manager at Hamdan Plaza Hotel Salalah, Oman HTG Group - Hamdan Plaza Hotel

Dec 2019 - Present

- Launched 50% unit's refurbishment and re-positioned the property in the market.
- Innovated the e-commerce and social media ranking in the top 10 in the area.
- Overhauled and re-structured sales & marketing boosting market share by 10%.
- Improved the SOP's & staff training and scored 10 points increase in guest satisfaction.
- Hotel & Hospitality Management
- Sales Strategy Management
- Budgeting & Forecasting
- Revenue Analysis, GOP, NOP & REV PAR.
- Restaurant Management
- Yield Management
- Customer Satisfaction
- MICROS & OPERA

General Manager at Gulf Inn Asdal Hotel Bahrain

GHG - Gulf Hotels Group

Dec 2018 - Nov 2019

- Deputize the Director of Operation for managing the hotels of the group as cluster GM for 5 properties.
- Tripled the highest profitability of 60% and positioned the property in the luxury market.
- Revitalized the luxury boutique hotel with the signature 1664 Bar resulted in 30% revenue increase.
- Increased revenues up by 40% and recognized by CEO.
- Achieved weekends 100% room occupancy over a period of 11 months 335 nights in the year.

General Manager pre-opening at Gulf Court Hotel Business Bay Dubai, UAE

GHG - Gulf Hotels Group Aug 2018 - Nov 2018

- Strengthened the hotel preopening strategic task force and pioneered the leisure market by 40%.
- Expedited planning of 270 keys, 6 outlets and bars, gaining a brand name in Dubai Business Bay.
- Awarded world hotels award during the strategic assignment with score of 95%.

Hotel Manager at Gulf Hotel Bahrain, convention & spa, Bahrain

GHG - Gulf Hotels Group

May 2016 - Jul 2018

- Authored great success increases in the e-commerce segment business by 15%.
- Attained winning 6 CITI Facts Awards.
- Formulated 1-2-1 heads of departments meetings & balance scored cards.

General Manager at Gulf Court Hotel Manama Bahrain

GHG - Gulf Hotels Group

May 2015 - Apr 2016

- Accelerated the re-branding of the property in a record time of 2 months.
- Effected the GHG brand standards in the property and generated revenue by 25%.

General Manager pre-opening at S Hotel Bahrain

S Hotel Bahrain

Mar 2014 - Apr 2015

- Completed the hotel design with the developer of 200 rooms, 6 outlets restaurant and bars.
- Introduced & trained 150 members on standard operating procedures and service manuals.

Area General Manager at City Seasons Hotel Dubai, Airport Road, UAE

CS - CITY SEASONS HOTELS Group

Dec 2012 - Feb 2014 (Manage 2 Hotels)

- Upgraded the personal guest services resulting in guest value for money up by 10%.
- Expanded and revamped the online segment and reflected in revenues by 20% increase.

General Manager at City Seasons Suites Dubai, 8th Street, UAE

CS - CITY SEASONS HOTELS Group

Sep 2011 - Nov 2012

- Introduced the SOP's guidelines for the property for standardization.
- Achieved ADR boost by 15%.
- Complemented the revenues by an increase of 17%.
- Introduced standards for controlled purchase management.

Cluster General Manager at Coral Hotel Muscat, Oman

HMH - Hospitality Management Holding

Jan 2009 - Aug 2011 (Manage 2 Hotels)

- Pioneered both hotel sales & marketing strategies and sales went up by 25%.
- Identified steps to reduce food cost by 13% resulting in an eventual 13% on the bottom line.

General Manager pre-opening at EWA Hotel Apartments, Bahrain

HMH - Hospitality Management Holding

Jan 2008 - Aug 2011

- Secured air-lines accommodation contract on year to year.
- 12% higher revenues than the year before.

Food and Beverage Manager at Novotel Al Dana Resort, Bahrain

ACCOR Group - Novotel Hotels

Jan 2005 - Dec 2007 (3 years)

- Beat last year bar sales by 10%.
- Reduced food, liquor and supply cost significantly and maintained a consistent 28% food and 18% liquor costs.
- Implemented service standards for all F&B associates & generated 30% guest satisfaction.

Education:

Greater Brighton Metropolitan College, UK

Hospitality Management Higher Diploma

Business Technology Education Council London, UK

BTEC Management Degree

The Royal Institute of Public Health & Hygiene, London, UK

Associate's degree

City & Guilds of London Art School, UK

Associate's degree in Culinary Arts

Hotel and Catering Bahrain, Bahrain

Hotel Operations Management Diploma

Bahrain Technical Institute, Bahrain

High School Diploma, Air Conditioning and Refrigeration

Skills:

Hospitality cluster Management • Profit & Loss Management • Strategic Sales • Pre-opening • Yield Management • Hotel Management • Food & Beverage • Revenue Analysis • Rooms Division • Front Office

Honors & Awards:

Hilton Maurice Reymond Award of Excellence Associate Talent Employee Award Certificate of Achievement Creating Brand Loyalty